[Music]
my valley is in a time of transition
sweetbriar grows next to my cottage and
it has long gone to seed
this morning i noticed there was rhyme
ice growing over the rose hips
just then the dawn came and before my
eyes it melted away
it's a very interesting and strange time
of year but cheerful
while i need to work full-time
diversifying the jobs i do has really
been the best choice for me and i've
quickly fallen more in love with my
local bookshop
[Music]
days are sunup to sundown i get to chat
with customers and find it to be a
lovely and mostly quiet type of work
which is unusual for retail jobs to say
the least
it makes me value the calm rhythm of my
small town
it suits me and of course has inspired
my writing and daydreaming
i enjoy these days spent with books
knowing i've had quite a few jobs in the
past that i deeply disliked
i think it can be easy to feel defined
by your job or not having a job or not
having the career success you wish you
had
and if you ever feel that especially if
you find yourself in a job that you
don't enjoy i'll share a line i recently
heard in a movie based off the book
stardust by neil gaiman
to paraphrase the line was in reference
to the main character tristan who was
working at a shop he really didn't like
it goes like this
if i know something from observing this
planet for so very long it's that humans
are never quite what they seem
there are shop boys then there are boys
who are simply working in a shop for the
time being
whether you enjoy your job or want to do
something different i think there's
wisdom in this line and remembering that
who you are isn't defined by your job or
achievements
it really doesn't matter too much in the
end or at least not as much as we may
think
if we can believe one thing it's that we
have intrinsic value no matter what
and if you're like tristan you take that
advice and decide to go on wild
adventures involving magic and stars and
sword fighting and all types of creative
pursuits
he's definitely one of my favorite
literary characters
[Music]
many independent bookshops around the
u.s have had trouble staying afloat
my bookshop has had a tough time during
the wildfire seasons that was so bad
this year and they barely got customers
if you want to support this or your
local bookshop i'm going to leave a link
to an equally affordable alternative to
audible called libro that supports your
local small businesses
i think that's so important right now i
know audible is able to afford a lot of
youtube sponsorships online i see them
everywhere so i just wanted to give my
unsponsored two cents and offer an
alternative
[Music]
i was gonna wear these glasses to film
but i'm realizing
they're very reflective so
we'll just
do this blind
if you hear chewing in the background
it's because mr darcy just got a bunch
of new fresh timothy hay
so i wanted to share a little bit of
working at the bookstore even though i'm
only working for the holidays i am
actually hoping to
potentially keep working there next year
it would be really nice i'm just
enjoying it so much and
the holidays even though they've been
pretty busy have been just so enjoyable
so far
i would say this retail job is by far
the one i've enjoyed the most of all the
ones i've done
and
there have been some really funny
challenges that have been presented to
me i as the holiday help i get paid
about fourteen dollars an hour
and
the average book in the store is about
fourteen dollars
and pretty much every hour
looking around i spot a new book that
i'd really like to read
so
um
yeah so i i could just be paid in books
at the rate that i'm amassing a list of
new things i want so in this video i
kind of wanted to share
some books that have been very
meaningful to me or that i am recently
reading that i've enjoyed and if you are
not a huge reader or you're just not
into book content don't worry i will be
back next week with my more normal
content so as you know
two of my favorite books of all time are
the snow child and once upon a river by
diane setterfield they are both just so
beautifully written they have kind of a
poetic feel to the style of writing and
they're so atmospheric and they both
have elements of kind of a connection to
another world
and kind of lifting the barrier between
the real world and another world it was
just so magical and i definitely
recommend those two for this time of
year and i recently started reading the
10 000 doors of january and i was told
that that book has a very similar feel
than those other two so i'm really
excited i just started it but i am
really enjoying it and the writing is
very artistic and just absolutely superb
some of my favorite books are books that
follow kind of
normal lives just of people who are just
living quiet simple
life experiences and yet they are also
in touch with something else something
more
i don't want to even say supernatural
but definitely of another world and it
just kind of adds this little element of
something really exciting
into
the life experience and the stories of
these people so i i just really love
that especially in the winter when it
just everything feels a lot more
kind of magical so
been really really enjoying that and
definitely when there's a spiritual
component and a bit of a narrative on
spirituality i really like as well so
anyway highly recommend those i do read
a lot of children's books i think
especially because
i assume it's perhaps because the
writers are really keeping in mind how
they felt about the world when they were
very young and they want to cater to
that
but i do find children's books to be
predominantly so hopeful and positive
and uplifting
and
i think that's such a beautiful message
and so many books for
teens and adults it's very common to
have much darker and depressing themes
and while those themes are definitely
very important and those books are
extremely well written and very
important i don't always want to
read stories that make me really sad
middle grade and why a books i feel come
back to that seed inside each of us that
wants to believe in a better world and i
think that's so important
i recently started enjoying graphic
novels a lot more i i used to never read
them and they've usually they've kind of
become more mainstream
and i really have been enjoying hilda
it's this a very adorable
graphic novel series about
initially a little girl who lives in the
wilderness and who is in touch with the
little people you know and these little
magical people that live in a partly
invisible world
and it's really sweet it has a
tv show adaptation on netflix and it's
just very calming and
just it has such a wholesome and sweet
sentiment i really enjoyed those books
so yeah if you enjoy
stories like that and kind of whimsical
wholesome you know adventure stories
definitely check those out i also
recently read my father's dragon which
is a book that i was raised on i used to
have it read aloud to me a lot and it's
hilarious and it's just so sweet it's
perfect for children and i just i love
it very very much
i also recently listened to the
audiobook of the very first book in the
binicula series and it is hilarious it's
about
a
cat and a dog who are living in a
household the family brings home a
rabbit who is not everything that he
seems and the cat and dog are just about
the funniest characters ever written i
just
i usually don't laugh in books but i
just found myself laughing all the time
while listening to that story so i
highly recommend that one in audiobook
form it is just so adorable i recently
started reading the fox and i and it
just seems to be such a beautifully
written nature story and i'm very
intrigued to buy it but one of the
reasons i
started reading it because i read a
couple other books in the nature section
that i was really surprised by how much
i love them others that come to mind are
the secret life of trees and winter
world winter world especially was a
little more scientific but i found it so
fascinating to read about how animals
behave in winter one thing i realized
recently is that the lake next to my
house
has a lot of painted turtles there are
these very beautiful gorgeous turtles
and there's dozens of them at the lake
and they're they're very sweet animals
they're skittish i always wondered what
happened to the turtles in winter
because they all disappear
and i was reading about how they slow
the mechanisms in their body so much
that they're able to drift down to the
bottom of the lake and the lake freezes
over
and they're able to survive just off of
their own energy
and
it's incredible to think that those
turtles are under water for four months
and they they do just fine and they
survive such a harsh condition and
it's just incredible to get insight into
all the mechanisms that animals and
nature uses to survive it's
it's amazing
i've always really enjoyed fantasy books
and i did recently start the name of the
wind which i was recommended by my
father and my brother because they both
love that book and i only just started
it but i can already tell it is
incredible it is
you know it is just so well written and
it is so exciting so i'm gonna keep
reading that one and give you guys an
update later
after working at a preschool i started
to really value children's books as well
even more than i did before and i have
collected quite a few that i really love
and one of them is called maybe and it's
just one of the most beautifully
illustrated books i've ever seen and
it's all about the power of imagination
and about your own potential
journey is another book that really
moved me and i think we as adults we
somehow think that once we grow out of
the children's book section or the
picture book section we are never
allowed to return because you know
unless we are buying books for children
and yet i think so many of those books
are so beautiful and meaningful and they
offer short concise
interesting stories that we can still
get a lot out of and maybe and journey
are two of those books that were that
for me
another beautiful book that i saw
recently was called honey smoke i think
hopefully i'm remembering that title
right
and it's about a little girl in her
quest to embrace who she is and her
curly hair
and the color of her hair and her skin
and just
that journey of self-love
self-acceptance and the universal truth
that
your story is your story and no one can
take that away from you
i wanted to recommend some books on
myths and legends about puerto rico as
well but i couldn't find any really good
ones that were in english and so i will
leave some information down below but i
just couldn't find any that i felt
comfortable recommending because
translations just don't always do
stories justice especially when they are
myths and legends that really rely on
specific words that might not have a
direct translation in english
so i i did keep that in mind but i did
share some books about just the history
anyway i have just about a thousand
other books i could talk about
and so i'm just going to try to cut it
off here these aren't books that i
particularly think changed my life are
huge
crazy amazing
important books for me but they are ones
that i've kind of read more recently and
that i really enjoyed anyway i wish you
all very well i hope you have a
wonderful day
i hope this was not too rambly for you
and i will see you next week take care
goodbye
you